[Music]
so in the next version of the rest
client module that will be released with
version 26 of business Central the rest
client module now supports cookies that
was already supported in the HTTP client
um in Al code but now it also made it
way
to the rest client
module um on the request and response
message code units you find several
functions to work with
cookies um you can set a cookie on a
request as you can see
here um so here it takes a a cookie
object as the parameter uh to set a
cookie on the request message if the
cookie already exists it will just be
replaced uh it's also possible to set a
cookie with uh a cookie name and a value
so you don't have to create a cookie but
if you want to set some extra properties
on the cookie like uh domain uh or
Secrets then you have to create a cookie
first and then use set cookie with the
cookie object um so that is to set
um cookies on outgoing requests messages
it also possible to um read cookies from
the response message there is a c cookie
names which give you a list of all the
cookies again find if um a certain
cookie is available or was returned in
the response message and then you can
get its value directly by getting value
on The Returned cookie or you store the
cookie in a cookie object is up to you
um if you do not test on a get cookie
name then uh this one is uh returning an
empty cookie in case it does not exist
so you have an empty value in that case
it's the same as if it didn't exist at
all or you got an empty cookie um you
can also um try to get a cookie uh with
is working like this then it returns a
Boolean um and you will get the Boolean
um or yeah if the cookie is true if the
cookie exists and you can get its value
it also possible to get a dictionary of
all cookies including their names uh as
the uh key of the dictionary and that is
wave the function get cookies so this uh
is not justk returning a list of cookie
names but gives you a full dictionary
which I think uh might be uh convenient
to work with so that is the first thing
that uh is new in the rest client uh the
next new thing is exception
handling previously if you call the uh
rest client functions here we have the
get S Json um but any get or post or any
command on the rest client returns um uh
or or they'll throw an error in case um
there is an issue with the connection um
which could be the um uh blocked by
environment or the connection
faiied um it didn't return or it didn't
throw an error in case the HTTP status
code was not in a 200 series which was
for a reason because you need to handle
that yourself but errors were raised for
um blocked by environment or connection
failed and there was nothing you could
do about it uh in case uh here uh with
the Json uh you want to return a Json
object and the Json was invalid then um
it would also uh throw an error or give
you back an uh an empty Jon object to uh
uh for you to handle it more gracefully
now now this uh behavior is still the
same but you can now get collected
errors So based on um this line of code
you see here um where you enable um
error collection the um rest client will
throw a collectible error yes or no
depending on this line it detects if you
are collecting errors and if that is the
case then the eror that uh
occur um or error conditions or
exceptions uh will throw an collectible
error rather than just a normal error
and that one uh can be catched here with
get collected errors there will always
be one error because uh it stops at the
first failure is not going to try
anything further because that doesn't
make any sense this part of the pattern
uh so you can always be sure that there
only will be one uh ex exception one
error in the error
collection um and in that um error so
this rest client error is an error info
on the custom dimensions of that error
info you can find an exception code and
an exception name the exception name is
there just for uh debuging reasons but
the exception code can be used used to
get um the corresponding enum the rest
client exception enum and you can get it
um conveniently from the rest client
exception Builder there's a function get
rest client exception and that one
Returns the enum and then you can test
the enum um what is it was it blocked by
environment uh was it the connection
field request field which means
HTTP um um error so not HP status 200 or
maybe the Json was invalid um and there
are uh a few other uh as well like
invalid XML or unknown
error uh so by um implementing this
pattern you are actually getting close
to what is known in CP code as the tri
catch pattern try catch uh code you try
a function and you catch the errors well
this is um pretty close to uh that
behavior and you can do this only by
adding the error Behavior line on top of
your
function so this hopefully opens more
possibility for you to gracefully um
handle several errors that can occur in
the r client um and it's all up to you
of course how you want to handle it uh
it's now in your hands hope you like it